thewhoot.com.au 2019-12-02

# Privacy Policy | The WHOot

Who Australia Pty Ltd A.C.N. 141 199 868 ( **we** , **us** , **our** , or **Who Australia** ) recognises and values the protection of your personal information. We are aware of our obligations under the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) and we will ensure that we fulfil our obligations under that Act.

We also recognise that you may have concerns about our collection of your personal information via our website, which is located at [www.thewhoot.com.au](https://thewhoot.com/) (the **Website** ) and how we may use that information.

We have implemented this Privacy Policy in order to inform you about how we will collect, store, use your personal information and under what circumstances we may disclose your personal information.

Please note that this Privacy Policy forms part of the Terms of Use document, which is displayed at the footer of the Website.

 **Information we collect from you**

From time to time, we may ask you to supply personal information such as your name, address, date of birth, telephone number or e-mail address. However, under no circumstances will we request or collect any information from you that may disclose your:

  * political, religious or philosophical beliefs or affiliations;
  * health and sexuality;
  * racial or ethnic origin; or
  * criminal convictions.

We may also conduct surveys or market research and may seek other information from you on a periodic basis. These surveys will provide us with information that allows improvement in the types and quality of services offered to you, and the manner in which those services are offered to you.

 **Personal information via the Website**

Most commercial websites use ‘cookies’, which are pieces of information that websites send to the browser and are stored in the computer hard-drive. Cookies make using the Website easier by storing information about your preferences on the Website. This allows the Website to be tailored to you for any of your return visits. Cookies will not identify you personally.

If you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter your security settings on your web browser to disable cookies or to warn you when cookies are being used. However, by disabling the cookie function in your web browser you may impede your ability to use parts of the Website.

 **Your option not to provide your personal information** ** **

Providing us with your personal information is absolutely optional, and whenever it is optional for you to provide us with your personal information, we will make this clear to you. When you provide us with your personal information, you are consenting to our storage, use and disclosure of that information as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

We may from time to time run competitions or offer additional benefits to you and we may ask you to provide us with your personal details for these purposes. Providing us with this information is absolutely optional to you. However, if you do not provide your personal information to us we may not be able to contact you or give you access to the additional benefits.

You may opt out of these additional communications at any time and can do so by emailing us.

Ad personalisation has been disabled for residents of California in order to comply with the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA).

 **Use and disclosure of your personal information**

Your personal information, including your e-mail address, will be used for the following primary purposes:

  1. to ensure the proper functioning of the Website;
  2. to ensure the proper functioning of the ‘The Whoot’ business; and
  3. to assist Who Australia with our marketing, planning, product development and research requirements.

We will not use or disclose (or permit the use or disclosure of) personal information that could be used to identify an individual member in any circumstances except:

  * to ensure the proper functioning of our business and the Website
  * to communicate promotional offers and special events to you;
  * where the law requires us, or authorises us to do so; or
  * where you have given express consent to us for a prescribed purpose.

We will not sell, distribute, rent, licence, disclose, share or pass your personal information onto any third parties, other than those who are contracted to us to keep the information confidential whether subject to a statute or a scheme which imposes similar restrictions to the National Privacy Principles contained in the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) regarding the handling of personal information.

 **Terms of Use**

We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that all information collected from you is accurate, up to date, complete and stored in a secure environment and accessed only by our authorised personnel.

Please note that no information transmitted over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. However, we will endeavour to protect your personal information as best as possible but we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to us, or receive from us. The transmission and exchange of information is carried out at your own risk.

 **Unsubscribing from our e-mail database**

To unsubscribe from our e-mail database, please send an e-mail to [unsubscribe@thewhoot.com.au](mailto:unsubscribe@thewhoot.com.au) with “UNSUBSCRIBE” typed into the subject line of the e-mail.

 **Accessing, correcting and updating your information**

You have the right to access the information that you provide to us.

If you wish to access, modify or remove any personal information that you have provided to us, please contact our Privacy Officer at [privacy@thewhoot.com.au](mailto:privacy@thewhoot.com.au).

 **Contacting us**

If you have any concerns or questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@thewhoot.com.au](mailto:privacy@thewhoot.com.au).

We reserve our right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Should any significant amendments occur, notification would be provided by publication on the Website. For further information about privacy, please refer to the Australian Privacy Commissioner’s website [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).

 _Privacy Policy last updated on 21 May 2018._
